## **Benjamin Powers**

## Sr. Frontend Developer

Well-qualified Frontend Developer familiar with wide range of programming utilities and languages. Knowledgeable of frontend and backend development best practices and has extensive experience in integration with various cutting-edge technologies including Blockchain, VR/AR and ML. Handles any part of process with ease, especially with React for frontend development. Collaborative team player with excellent technical abilities offering 7 years of related experience.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## Sr. Frontend Developer

07/2020 - 12/2022

Myria Software, New York, NY, Remote

**Tech stack:** React, React Hooks, Redux, MUI, SASS, Micro-Frontend, TypeScript, JavaScript, Node.js, Express, MongoDB, GraphQL, Solidity, Ethereum, Hardhat, Web3.js

- Increased customer rating and satisfaction from 30% to 60% by implementing new ideas in smart contracts for NFT minting
- Collaborated with the UX/UI design teams to improve the website and applications, increasing conversion rates by 25%
- Built and maintained strategic relationships with potential investors and business partners and brainstormed new ideas
- Collaborated with colleagues from other teams to participate in the creation and testing of new software applications
- Increased 24% faster loading time and time spam per visit by +70 seconds in 5+ projects

Product url: https://thor.financial

### Sr. Full Stack Developer

06/2017 - 06/2020

CIBC, Downtown Toronto, M5L Ontario

**Tech stack:** React, Redux, Vue.js, Nuxt.js, Tailwind CSS, Node.js, Express, TypeScript, JavaScript, Redis, GraphQL, Restful API, WebSocket, MongoDB, AWS, Jenkins

- Increased daily traffic from 45% to 80% in E-commerce platforms by redesigning existing websites to improve user experience and incorporated SEO
- Implemented 14 new features as defined and scoped by a product team of 12
- Collaborated with 2 different development teams on 4 new project designs and feature improvements
- Suggested 20+ improvements to product design and functionality as informed by user-experience reporting
- Collaborated with 4 client service teams to understand and solve bottlenecks and proposed feature expansions
- Architected, implemented, and maintained 5 performant and scalable data-processing back-end systems

Product url: <a href="https://private-wealth.us.cibc.com">https://private-wealth.us.cibc.com</a>

### **Frontend Developer**

AWS Amplify, Jenkins

07/2016 - 05/2017

Bmo Harris Bank N.A, Downtown Toronto M5L Ontario **Tech stack:** React.js, HTML5, Bootstrap, SASS, JavaScript, jQuery, Redux, Git, GCP,

CONTACT

- · San Francisco, CA
- · +1 (352) 234 4952
- linkedin.com/in/benjamin-p-047284257/
- susanowithmail@gmail.com

#### **SKILLS**

- React, React Hooks, Next.js
- Redux, React Context
- · JavaScript, TypeScript
- HTML5, CSS3, Tailwind CSS,
  SCSS, MUI
- · Node.js, Express, Nest.js
- · Microservices, Micro-Frontend
- · GraphQL, Restful API
- MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB
- · AWS Amplify, AWS Lambda
- · Chart.js, D3.js
- Solidity, Hardhat
- · Web3.js

#### **EDUCATION**

# Hong Kong University of Science and Technology

Bachelor of Computer Engineering

Awarded Best Engineering Award in Robocon 2013 Hong Kong Contest

#### LANGUAGE

- English
- · Chinese

- Added an additional average of 25% increase in annual company revenue with an average of 15 clients per month
- Developed 10+ cluster projects and utilized public cloud, computing infrastructure services
- Designed 20+ front-end Web Interface for engineers and test-ops to control and monitor the onboard system
- Analyzed and optimized performance bottlenecks in 8+ existing backend systems, such as database queries and storage solutions, to increase responsiveness

Product url: <a href="https://bmo.com">https://bmo.com</a>

## **Jr. Frontend Developer**

05/2015 - 05/2016

Wisers Information Ltd, Tung Wai Commercial Bldg, Hong Kong **Tech stack:** React, Next.js, JavaScript, Express.JS, Firebase, MongoDB

- Increased ratings by an average of over 20% annually through optimizing performance and delivery of resources using Webpack.
- Worked with 8+ teams to build web-based tools to facilitate their development lifecycle
- Collaborated with 3 SRE teams of 6 to identify issues and increase the stability, performance, and efficiency of private computing services

Product url: <a href="https://www.swell.com">https://www.swell.com</a>

#### **HIGHLIGHTS**

- · Test Driven Development
- · Revenue generation
- · Clean architecture
- · High quality code
- · Deadline focused work
- Open-mind with new technologies
  and challenges
- · Team work & communication
- · Problem solving
- · Creative Idea